<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <title>Storm Water Projects</title>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>Volusia County Stormwater Projects. Maintained by Volusia County Public Works.</abstract>
            <purpose>Volusia County, FL stormwater projects.</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>Open Data</themekey>
                <themekey>Hub</themekey>
                <themekey>Volusia County</themekey>
                <themekey>hub public works</themekey>
                <themekey>drainage</themekey>
                <themekey>projects</themekey>
                <themekey>hurricane</themekey>
                <themekey>flood</themekey>
                <themekey>surge</themekey>
                <themekey>Backup</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Other Constraints</accconst>
        <useconst>Volusia County, FL shall not be held liable for improper or incorrect use of the data described and/or contained herein. These data and related graphics (i.e. GIF or JPG format files) are not legal documents and are not intended to be used as such. The information contained in these data is dynamic and may change over time. The data are not better than the original sources from which they were derived. It is the responsibility of the data user to use the data appropriately and consistent within the limitations of geospatial data in general and these data in particular. The related graphics are intended to aid the data user in acquiring relevant data; it is not appropriate to use the related graphics as data. Volusia County, FL gives no warranty, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy, reliability, or completeness of these data. It is strongly recommended that these data are directly acquired from Volusia County, FL Geographic Information Services and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. Although these data have been processed successfully on computer systems at Volusia County, FL facilities, no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the utility of the data on other systems for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty. This disclaimer applies both to individual use of the data and aggregate use with other data.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Volusia County IT/GIS</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Brandon Barnett</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>Information Technology GIS Section Manager</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>119 W. Indiana Ave.</address>
                    <city>DeLand</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>32720</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>386-736-5922</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>386-822-5728</cntfax>
                <cntemail>bbarnett@volusia.org</cntemail>
                <hours>Monday-Friday: 8am-5pm</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>Volusia County, FL</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20220427</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
